Krishnokoli Roy Chakraborty

User Experience Designer

Krishnokoli is a product and experience designer, with a relentless passion for interactive narrative design, using emerging technologies. She has over 7 years of professional experience in product design, visual design, interaction design, and motion graphics. She is also experienced in working with web or mobile based technologies (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React). Krishnokoli's portfolio encompasses an array of multidisciplinary design skills to realize meaningful design solutions for an inclusive and diverse audience. She has exceptional leadership, communication, and collaboration skills.

CONTACT

+1 416 887 3483

<u>amikrishnokoli@gmail.com</u>

Toronto, Ontario

krishnokoli.format.com

in <u>linkedin.com/in/krishnokoli</u>

EDUCATION

Master's Degree

Digital Futures OCAD University, 2020 - 2022

Bachelor's Degree

Graphic Design National Institute of Design, India 2014 - 2018

DESIGN SKILLS

- Visual Design
- Information Graphics
- Illustration
- Motion Graphics
- Typography
- UX Design
- Interaction Design
- Product Design
- Design Research
- Critical Thinking
- Narrative Design

WORK EXPERIENCE

UX DESIGNER

TALENTICA SOFTWARE, INDIA | 2018 - 2020 | Full-Time

- Winner of 2 consecutive Spot Awards since 2018 2020 for exceptional performance and client satisfaction.
- **Subject matter expert** on visual / communication design, and design for rich interactive experiences.
- Worked alongside a team of graphic designers and front-end developers
 using agile methodologies and design thinking principles in a fast-paced
 agency environment.
- Worked directly with clients to develop an understanding of project needs.
- Executed comprehensive research to identify client needs and pain points and establish a design solution through critical thinking.

GUEST FACULTY

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF DESIGN, INDIA | 2020 | Contract

- Curriculum development for under-graduate-level design research course
- Course instructure, student development discussion,
- · Student Evaluation, grading and documentation

STUDENT COLLABORATOR

OCAD UNIVERSITY, TORONTO | 2021 - present | Part-Time

- Research and development of creative content for the Decolonial
 Approaches project, like creating personal and subjective Land
 Acknowledgements, and conducting Interviews with indigenous artists.
- Contributing towards developing a curriculum, as an international student and a person of colour, for other new international students and faculty, to inform about decolonization practices, and indigenous culture.

VISUAL DESIGNER

PLAYPOWER LABS, SAN FRANCISCO & INDIA | 2018 | Internship

- Worked directly with CTO to develop the visual experience of the online learning platforms for school children.
- Devised and produced original narrative and visual experiences in association with key stakeholders.

TOOLS

- Figma
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe Aftereffects
- Adobe Premier Pro
- Adobe Dimensions
- Adobe XD
- Sketch
- Unity
- Vuforia
- AR Design Tools
- HTML / CSS
- AR.js
- P5.js
- Arduino
- Java
- JavaScript
- Atlassian Suite
- Miro
- Trello
- Microsoft Suite

LANGUAGES

- English
- Bengali
- Hindi

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

RIGGER HOUSE, INDIA | 2017 - 2018 | Freelance

 Designed visuals and digital graphics for event spaces and media sets for companies like Alt Balaji, Viacom18 and MTV.

JUNIOR GRAPHIC DESIGNER

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF DESIGN, INDIA | 2016 - 2017 | Freelance

 Designed media articles and collaterals for the Launching of the prestigious Lalbhai Museum in Ahmedabad, India, under the guidance of Prof. Tanishka Kachru and renowned architect Rahul Mehrotra.

GRAPHIC DESIGN INTERN

KABES MEDIA, INDIA | 2016 | Freelance

- Worked with clients to develop an understanding of project needs, in terms of deliverables like business collaterals, media infographics, and presentations.
- Executed comprehensive research to identify client needs and pain points and establish a design solution through.

LINKS

https://krishnokoli.format.com (Portfolio)

https://linkedin.com/in/krishnokoli_LinkedIn)